[Music]
thank you
hello and welcome to BQ Prime we are
doing earnings with BQ and our guest
today is Mr gopal balachandran the CFO
of ICICI Lombard welcome to the show sir
good morning
uh so we've had a great quota with our
after tax profits jumping 36 year on
your
um to the entire year so what has
literally contributed to this growth
so uh so that's a great start uh so I
think if you look at it from an Isis
Central onward standpoint uh not just
for this quarter or just for this year
in general over the last several years
since the time we have been operations
we have always focused on profitable
growth as a theme
uh the growth of whatever 35 or 40 is
more an outcome but fundamentally as an
institution I think what we have largely
kind of as I said State invested is to
grow each segment of businesses from an
underwriting lens and therefore to that
extent stay invested in building those
portfolios of risks which eventually
contributes to let's say and profitable
outcome and that's where you get to see
possibly an increase in the overall
profit numbers it's been across board
aided by different segments of business
that we underwrite and uh the eventual
outcome as I said is more than an
absolute growth in profits I think one
of the objectives that we have also
spoken about is to sustain uh the kind
of return on Equity that we can exhibit
to our stakeholders now that if you see
has been at about 17.7 percent uh for
let's say the year gone by and uh in
general we have talked about sustaining
the earnings over longer periods in the
range of High Teens which is between 16
to 18 percent
okay uh so then our net premiums have
seen a horizon around 14 so
um in 36 what has actually really
contributed to it is it that the
combined ratio has uh improved or is
there some other element to this
so obviously when you look at the
numbers uh I think uh as I said insofar
as the overall gross premium income is
concerned we had a growth of almost
about 17 on a full year basis and
obviously the net premium what you are
referring to is the function of the grow
growth in premiums that one had seen yes
you're equally right when you look at
the combined ratios on a foliar basis
last year combined ratios we were at
about 108 108.8 the current year we are
at 104.5 uh so hence to that extent
that's obviously is an important
influencer when you look at the overall
uh where the things have played out but
as I said it's been an across board we
have equally kind of focused
significantly hard on maintaining the
right product mix
two obviously we have kind of invested
significantly on some of our claim
servicing capabilities by virtue of
which we have been able to keep majority
of the loss ratios under check
and three the sum of the Investments
that we have been doing on distribution
and processes they have kind of started
to kind of put out uh Positive Growth
momentum and therefore the overall
efficiency in operations is what one has
also been able to exhibit so it's been
across board is the way how things have
played out and hence to that extent is
where we are kind of quite excited as we
head into the next year as well
I sat until you've spoken about
efficiencies uh there's a question on
the expenses of management which I think
stand at 29.6 for the year
um which is almost in the range of the
mandated 30 percent so does it mean that
going forward we will see an improvement
of further adoption and um you know
because we're barely in check so uh what
is what are the steps that are being
planned towards this again that's a
great question I think so what you're
referring to possibly in terms of the
threshold is a new expensive management
guideline that has come into Force
effective uh April 23 as a part of that
I think that's again a great development
when you look at it from a market
perspective because the regulatory
really has spelled out to say that they
would kind of watch out for companies
based on a single limit on expensive
management which is presently put at 30
for multi-line players like us uh having
feedback I think if you look at it from
an ICC Lombard standpoint again not just
this year consistently across years as a
company we have always operated a
threshold which has been less than the
30 levels uh in the market there are
many players and this is public
information in terms of what levels of
expense management are they operating at
there are players in the market who are
at levels which are Beyond 30 and
clearly there The Regulators talked
about a Glide path for some of those
players to come back to a threshold
Which is less than 30. that we believe
it's an area of opportunity because once
the market starts to get a bit more
reasonable in terms of pricing and more
importantly let's say the cost of doing
business that by itself presents an
opportunity for companies like ICC
Lombard which have its brand Capital
solvency and efficiency in operations so
hence from a market perspective we again
believe this is a great positive
development to your other point on
specifics for ICC cell over of course
yes I think we will continue the number
of 29.6 that you see that we put out in
the public domain is again as I said
well within the threshold of the limits
that is presently existing and two
having said that this number also
includes the affronting of expenses that
were required to make for any
Investments that we make in distribution
while the benefit of revenues can come
through over a period of time for
example what we have been talking
through over the last several quarters
is let's say addition of head count uh
in terms of employees on the retail
Health the indemnity segment now the
moment you get employees onboarded you
have the costs coming and hitting your
friend whereas the benefit in the form
of revenues will come through over a
period of time so when you look at that
number of 29.6 it has the elements of
Investments that we have been doing in
various areas that we have spoken about
and over a period of time the benefits
of revenues will come through and hence
is what I made a reference to say that
we will possibly get into further
efficiency in operations
so you're saying that all The Upfront
costs have been incurred and that you're
not going to make any such big
expenditure going forward does it mean
that and where exactly have we spent
this amount on distribution then so for
the amount for the for the Investments
that we had kind of spoken about last
year all of those costs have been kind
of factored in however it was not
one-off expenses
it's a continuing one again let me kind
of make it clear if you look at on the
retail Health Indemnity our market share
is three percent now that's a segment
where there is clearly an area of
opportunity where we're investing a lot
and we will continue to do so so any
incremental Investments it's not just a
one-off investment that we did last year
it's an ongoing one and therefore why
requirement those costs will come and
hit us offer it but the good news is the
incremental revenues that we were
expecting out of let's say some of the
past Investments we have started to play
out and hence we are seeing efficiency
in operations okay so then we'll still
be within the limits
um so now what are we doing in terms of
strategy because what I understand is
you have
you have it so you have the Liberty to
distribute commission among your various
segments so uh what is uh currently I
think motor and health are a couple of
focus areas
so is it that there'll be more
commission going towards that uh do we
have some strategy in place as the
company
of course I think if you ask me at a
macro level I think there are three or
four key preferred segments as you
rightly mentioned which is motor health
and Commercial lines uh having said that
there are multiple sub segments within
each of them so within motor you have
the private car you have two wheeler you
have the commercial vehicles within
Health you have the retail Health you
have corporate you have some of the
b2b2c uh segments and so on and so forth
within commercials there are multiple
segments that we kind of operate at now
each of them is something that we look
at as an area of opportunity the good
news again is when you look at the
market potential uh forget about this
year this year the market grew up
roughly about 16.4 percent if you look
at for the last 15 years since the time
the sector was freed from pricing the
industry has grown at a compounded rate
of almost 15 percent
there is no reason why this Market
should not continue to exhibit that
similar kind of a growth in that 50 to
20 range and from an Isis Lombard
positioning I think we are kind of well
poised to again capture the opportunity
for growth and possibly grow faster than
the market and therefore we will
obviously use all our delivers to make
sure that we are kind of focusing on the
right product segments keeping in mind
the original point that I made which is
underwriting the businesses will be
profitable growth lens that's the way we
kind of look at it and hence into so far
as the requirement of compliance to
regulations are concerned as I said even
in the past we've always been within the
norms
going at will continue to do so and you
use the flexibility that the regulator
has given to kind of get invested in the
right product segments that is viable
for us
uh so uh so my question actually stems
from the fact that you know a motor
operating profit year on year has been
down
so uh is it that we're going to be
paying more attention to motor going
ahead uh if yes are we looking at
commercial or private segment I believe
commercial vehicle is one sector which
you are looking closely at also for
health
um the kind of recovering so are we are
we putting more resources towards Health
just trying to understand how how are
your commission expense is going to be
you know what is it going to what is
going to be your future strategy so to
say yeah as I said I think the focus
will continue to be in each of those
three macro segments that I spoke about
having said that specifically let me
address on motor now from an iPhone
standpoint the approach that we have
taken about again not just now even in
the past what we have done effectively
is whenever the market has got very very
competitive at that point of time we
have always been a bit guarded and
cautious as I said keeping in mind the
handwriting objectives which is why you
see possibly us not necessarily growing
or maybe underperformed in the industry
in the motor segment but having said
that we continue to make investments in
expanding distribution whether it is in
terms of the number of dealerships that
we work with
or whether it is with respect to the
number of agents who will help us Source
premiums We are continuing to make
investments in expanding those
distribution channels and hence as and
when the market kind of turns around we
are better placed to capitalize the
opportunity for growth what we've seen
so far as the potential is concerned
same thing holds good for health as well
in terms of the explanation that I said
for retail Health that's a continuing
Investments that we are doing on one
adding head count first who in turn will
go out on the market to get agents on
board who in turn will kind of start
becoming far more productive and
therefore to that extent they should see
incremental efficiency in operations
commissions is more a Fallout of the way
we want to kind of run each of those
businesses but as I said larger
objective is obviously we will
channelize the overall limits that has
been laid out by regulation in the
segments of businesses which are
preferred for us okay
um also crop has been profitable so are
we going to see any more Investments
towards it uh
so again if you would have kind of heard
us talking about crop as a segment uh
obviously we will stay invested in that
particular segment as well having said
that what we have clearly spoken about
is the fact that crop in the overall
Revenue mix is likely to be a single
digit number the current year if you
would have seen that number is close to
about four to five percent of the
overall uh Revenue mix uh and hence
that's the approach that you would want
to see we will obviously the government
is also from time to time being making
changes to the crop insurance scheme and
hence to that extent basis the
opportunity that one sees is where we
will look at writing this particular
portfolio but as I said in terms of the
overall Revenue mix uh it is going to be
a single digit contribution to the
numbers in terms of profitability again
as we keep saying crop is an outcome
definitely cannot be looked at on a
year-on-year basis because the weather
Gods can be kind to us in one year but
in the next year possibly as you get to
head into fi 24 already we are hearing
signs of l l n o possibly having an
impact hence to that action we have to
be looking at the outcome of this
particular segment over longer periods
rather than just over a one year Horizon
and uh so have we had any change in
distribution strategy I mean we're
already we're adding head counts but are
we also looking at more Banker
Partnerships uh is there any change well
again that's a great that's a great
question because again from an ICC
Lombard standpoint uh we've always
looked at ourselves as a multi-product
multi-distribution channel company
because typically you have to look at
where the customer is located at and
which is why I say we have to pay
multi-channel approach you see a
customer touch point at dealership you
see a customer creating access through
agents you get a customer getting access
through bank Partners the point that you
made is very very relevant and in that
context on the banking side particularly
uh very recently the regulator is again
kind of made a relaxation in the right
direction of possibly making even Bank
distribution more or less an open
architecture which currently had a cap
of three insurance companies which a
bank would partner with that has been
kind of increased to nine each so hence
to that extent but having said that if
you look at it from like this is a
number standpoint amongst the large
private Banks we already had an access
to whether it was our own parent HDFC
Bank axis Bank yes Bank idfc Standard
Chartered and so on and so forth but
definitely this increase in the open
architecture regulatory change is again
a welcome Direction in the right step
and uh we are kind of looking for that
again as an area of opportunity in terms
of increasing access or increasing
channel of access more importantly we
also are a firm believer of digital as
well in terms of the businesses that we
can Source even through our own website
which is isuzulumba.com so hence to
answer your point we will continue to be
a multi-channel driven approach and
we're kind of investing not just in
looking at Bank distribution but equally
kind of staying invested in all touch
points wherever we are we can possibly
get a customer acquired with
answer my last question uh what would be
your guidance for the upcoming year
so as we keep saying which is why I was
wanting to give you that 15-year number
which is what I kind of said uh if you
look at it from a market perspective the
market uh has grown at 15 kagger over a
15-year cycle now there is no reason in
looking at maybe the again the macro
level picture India shining is something
that everyone talks about and hence to
that extent there is no reason why this
Market on a steady state forget next
year even from a medium to long term
should continue to grow in that
trajectory 50 to 20 percent uh and in
terms of ICC Lombard's thought process
we have always looked at growing
ourselves slightly faster than the
market even for the current year if
you'd have seen we kind of grew faster
than the industry uh and obviously we
had a small increase in market share and
therefore we will continue to look at
from a Topline perspective slightly to
grow faster than the market
subject to of course the market being
reasonable in terms of its competitive
intensity having said that what we've
also talking to spoken to the market in
terms of the combined ratio objective if
you would have seen for us we are
currently operating at a combined ratio
which is around 104 over the next two
years we would obviously want we want to
stay again we have been talking about it
with the market uh in the next two years
we would want to see a Glide path of
that combined go down to 102 so that's
the thought process in terms of combined
and finally we always believe as I
mentioned earlier as well is a
sustainable return on Capital which will
continue to be in High Teens uh which
within that range of about 16 to 18 but
that's again a function of what kind of
product mix that we underwrite these are
three broad levers that one would kind
of look at in terms of how one is
positioning our systems account
okay so much so it was the pleasure
thank you so much
[Music]